you know, some costly turnovers, some
big plays that ended up coming back. We
had a bunch of injuries throughout.
Everybody ended up returning except for
Kevin Dodson. Um, you know, but we
really found a way, you know, I thought
the defense was outstanding. They did a
great job just getting stop in, stop
out. What a job by Lamb Man. It was an
unbelievable recovery by Fist there,
too. Um, and then I thought Matthew
Stafford was in great command all day.
You know, they were obviously in
excellent rush. Um they did a good job
of being able to apply pressure where we
can do, you know, a better job in some
different situations, but he came up
with clutch play after clutch play. I
thought he was seeing the field really
well. Um you know, really awesome for
him to go over 60,000 yards. That's
unbelievable. Um real testament to the
consistency of what he's done. Uh Puka
had some big time plays. I thought
Devonte came up clutch in some critical
situations. And then obviously Kairen
always runs so well. I thought it was an
unbelievable job by him. Not a great
call by me on the fourth and one. They
ended up jumping the defensive end
outside and Kairen found a way to make
it right. Puka kind of trying to stay
connected on Hunter, but um you know,
our guys found a way and that's what
it's about. I think he learned a lot
about this group today. Um you know, and
there's a mental toughness, there's a
resilience and there's an opportunity
for us to learn a lot. I mean, there's a
ton of things that, you know, when you
talk about what do good teams do and
smart teams that we can really learn
from, uh but I'm damn grateful to be
able to do it. um you know after getting
the result that we want um it's a cool
locker room in there and there's a ton
of respect coming from me to Demo and
his group and it's a good football team
they came out so physically um how did
you feel your group respond and that
game was kind
>> yeah I I thought they responded well
Jordan I thought they did a great job
you know and obviously you know we knew
it would be that kind of game that's the
style that they play with um you know we
like that kind of style as well I think
we're a tough football team they're a
tough football team. I think there's so
many great things that we can really
learn from situationally. I mean, you're
going in to basically try to put the
game away. We end up turning it over on
an early down when we were in a good
efficient situation. We had the hold
where Jay Wit gets down inside the 10
yardd line, the kickoff return that
comes back. You know, we had a personal
foul that extended that drive there. Um,
you know, and so there's just a lot of
really cool things for us to be able to
learn from. And you feel a lot better,
you know, when the guys just found a
way. And there was a lot of reasons uh
for them to think, "Oh man, things
aren't necessarily going in our favor."
But I never felt our group flinch. I
never felt our group uh separate. I
thought the defense did an unbelievable
job uh really keeping our team in the
football game. I thought teams was uh
really good. Josh Cardi, what a job he
did with the kickoffs. I mean, to be
able to have, you know, some of those
opportunities where you put them at the
20 yardd line based on if it ends up
being a normal touchback, it's at the
35. So, a lot of things that I'm looking
forward to being able to learn from and
um and that's exactly what we'll do.
>> We'll get Jim Hill. We'll get Jim Hill
next. Coach, can you talk about
>> Jim Hill? You got the next question. All
right. Nice. Okay.
>> And thank you, too.
>> Thank you. All right. Good to see you,
man.
>> You talk about the mental toughness of
your club, which allows them to get into
slumps and then get out of it.
>> Yeah. And that's big, Jim. I mean,
because there's es and flows throughout
the course of a season, throughout the
course of games. Um, and especially just
today where you could really feel like
there would have been a lot of reasons
to feel like, oh man, we're not
necessarily uh finishing some drives.
We're not doing things that are in
alignment with maybe what we've become
accustomed to doing. Uh, but what we are
accustomed to doing is hanging in there,
staying tough, staying in the fight,
finding a way to be able to finish games
out. I thought it was awesome that, you
know, you talk about finishing a game
and we get the stop when we had to where
Land Man gets the timely punch. Fisk
makes a great recovery. We get a penalty
on first down that that stops the clock
as well. You're thinking, man, that is
not a good situation to be in. Kairen
Williams has two really, really tough
runs. Um, and then Matthew and Puka end
up closing the game out. Is an
unbelievable job by all Jackson as well
being able to secure that edge to allow
him to kind of come out little fake to
the right, boot back out to the left,
and find Puka as he outflanked off of a
similar action before. Um, so I was so
proud of the group. Um, and that's uh,
you know, that's going to be something
that's going to be a separator for us if
we can continue to callus ourselves in
the right way um, as we navigate through
this season.
>> During camp about the spark that Nate
brought to this defense, what kind of
tone does that type of play at the end
of this game set for him and the defense
moving forward?
>> I'll tell you what's cool about it,
Adam, is we always talk about practice
performance and preparation equal in
game reality. That's what this guy's
done. Um, he has gotten more punch outs
than anybody. Uh he has just a great
feel for it. He's so intentional and I
think it's rubbed off on the rest of the
group. Um and he got it at a critical
time. You know, you talk about
competitive greatness that was on
display. Uh he's such a great
communicator. He's just got a great way
about himself where he can know how to
authentically connect with a bunch of
different guys. He's got a swag and a
toughness that he plays with that
resonates with his teammates. And uh you
know, he closed the game out in a big
way for us today.
>> Coach, Texas shot uh who catches a post
in the first half. takes a shot, ends up
going to the locker room, getting
evaluated for a concussion. He ends the
game, 10 catches, 130 yards. Can you
talk to me about how he exemplifies and
embodies the toughness of this team?
>> I think he just really said it with the
question, you I mean, you look at
everything that he's about, you know,
he's catching a third down slant similar
to what Jordan S where, you know,
Devonte catches a slant. It's a bang
bang play where guys are, you know,
getting collisioned and, you know, Puka
comes back, he gets stitched up, um, and
he immediately makes his presence felt,
catches a couple seams, catches a big in
cut off of a play action, uh, just makes
play after play. When the ball's in his
hands, good things happen, you know, and
then the other thing, too, is is he sets
up the way to close the game because
he'll stick his face on people in the
run game. I mean, he's as tough as it
gets. He checks every box you're looking
for. I love this guy. Love what he
represents. His energy, his play style,
his mental and physical toughness. He's
he's a dog and and I'm grateful to have
him on our group. And I know his
teammates and coaches feel the same way.
You
>> think about franchise, you think about
offense, you Stafford, Bua, now Devonte.
What does it mean that the defense kind
of you guys rolled in today?
>> Yeah, I think it's great, Timmy. I I
think that was the kind of game that it
it had to be and and there was some
opportunities for us to score some more
points. Um you know, but we're
interested in being a team that stays
connected, can win a bunch of different
types of games. And so I know I know
what you're asking and it was awesome to
be able to lean on the defense. They
kept us in that game. Um in spite of us
having some uncharacteristic execution
where we got a chance to score in the
red zone at the end of the game with
about four minutes left and we end up
turning it over. Um you look at the
penalty where we had the third and two
got Jay Whit you know wide open and he
takes that thing inside the 10 and then
you're getting yourself bumped back and
so uh there's just a lot of really good
learning options but to lean on the
defense I thought Chris Schula his staff
defensive players they did a great job
um really proud of that group and that's
been consistent with what they've shown
throughout the course of camp about the
offensive line the great job they did
today guys trying to score
>> they they did a really good job it's an
excellent front you know I thought Rob
Havenstein played excellent I hope K do
Kevin Dodson is okay But for Bo Li to
come in and play left and right guard,
what a credit to Stephen Aila as well.
You know, you look at he comes out of
the game, he was trying to really push
through. Felt like putting Bo in there
just with the way that he was feeling
was going to be better. And then he had
to come back in after Kevin Dodson comes
out. Coleman Shelton was tough as hell,
you know, and then you can't say enough
about all Jackson and what he was able
to do. I mean, this guy has a week of
practice. He goes against, you know,
some of the best players in the NFL and
they're rotating a bunch of different
guys, but he's lining up against Hunter.
He's lining up against Anderson. They've
got great guys that come in and
supplement them as well. And uh and he
was outstanding. I thought he played a
really complete game. So was really
proud of that group. Ryan Wendell does a
great job with that group as a whole.
And they were gritty. They found a way.
And then there'll be some cool learning
ops as well.
>> Did you notice Matthew's back bothering
you at all?
>> No. Did you? Looked pretty good to me.
You know, and he took some shots, popped
back up. I thought, you know, and and I
don't know that the stats will
necessarily reflect it in terms of a
bunch of yards. This guy was in total
command today. thought he played
excellent, kept the ball out of harm's
way. Um, you know, I could I put him in
a bad situation where we took that sack
where we were in kind of that fringe
area on the third down and four. That
was dumb by me. Um, but he did a great
job. I thought he made the plays that he
was supposed to make. Um, you know, was
excellent with his timing and rhythm. I
thought the operation was really good.
He's a stud. Um, and he was key and
critical and and to be able to put the
game away. Thought, you know, we really
we were at our best when we put the game
in his hands while still being smart and
having some good balance. Um, but he
made, you know, a bunch of big time
plays and we had to have all of them
other than a bad sneak that he had. That
was a bad call, too. All right.
>> Talking about the mental toughness. How
much of that starts with Matthew?
>> Uh, I think a lot of it. You know, I
think your your leaders, you know, they
end up embodying and becoming really the
personality that the team takes on. And
so really grateful to have somebody
that's as resilient, as steady, um, as
you know, calm in the midst of the chaos
as as what he is. but he's also got this
fire and this competitiveness that I
think is great for this game. And so we
got a lot of guys like that, but
certainly Matthew is uh it's a reason
why he's basically voted unanimously as
a captain year in and year out since
he's been here. Um and so we're really
grateful to have him leading the way.
>> So you see out of his connection with
Devonte today.
>> Yeah, I thought it was great. There was
a bunch of big time plays, you know, and
then I thought one of the huge plays in
the second half that was critical. I
mean, what a freaking catch by Devonte
on the one where I mean, he just took
that right off the grass. Yes, we were
in a bad situation. It was a shitty
first down call that I had on the
screen, you know, and then you guys, you
agree. You think it was a shitty call,
huh? All right. Well, I agree with you,
too. So, but he ended up, you know, that
play was big and that ended up leading
to points where we end up getting a
touchdown to Davis Allen. Um, you know,
and then he makes a couple plays where
he catches a Sluggo. You could see the
respect they had for him. Stingley was
traveling with him today, you know, and
uh and he's a great player. Uh there's
going to be some things that we can
learn from to be able to continuously
get him involved. Uh, but I thought he
made some big time third downs. Um, and
had that key in cut. You know, he's he's
a stud. You know, really grateful and
excited about continuing to be able to
build with him.
>> All right. You got nothing after the
shitty play call. Thank you guys.
It was great. Um I don't take uh you
know take it for granted. Um I love
being out there with those guys. I love
getting to work with them and um you
know just happy that I was able to kind
of get through what you know was going
on and and uh a lot of support from a
lot of people, teammates, coaches,
trainers, everybody. uh family. Um a lot
of a lot of appreciation goes to those
people for helping me and and um put a
bunch of work in, was able to get back
to this point and just happy to do it. I
love being out there. I love playing. Um
NFL football is hard. That's a really
good football team. We played, you know,
I think we had, you know, 21 to 28
points probably out there if we don't
have, you know, a couple things where we
hurt ourselves. Um and which is great.
You got to learn from stuff. Um find
ways to win games in September and uh we
were able to do that today. Unbelievable
effort by our defense. Um, can't say
enough about it. Um, timely. I mean, lay
man making that punch out was so cool.
Um, so just happy to be uh, you know,
where I'm standing right now.
>> How do you describe Matthew what you saw
from where he leaves, he's getting
stitches, and then to come back and have
that type of game?
>> Yeah, you know, he's a he's a special
player. He's a special person on our
team. Um,
you know, his game his game comes to
life on Sundays. you know, he goes out
there in practice and, you know, he's
he's working, he's doing all the stuff,
he's making plays and all that, but when
it becomes tackle football is when Puka
Nakua's game comes to life. And we're
we're really we're blessed to have him
um as a player, but as a person, too,
and as a competitor, um just the person
that he is day in and day out and then
what we get to, you know, what we get to
go out there and battle with on Sundays,
man, it's it's special. And uh I think
everybody in our locker room, I know
everybody in our locker room really
appreciates him. Um, and today's just,
you know, it's going to be another one
of those stories in a probably a really
long successful career of remember the
time opening day I had to do this, that,
and the other to get back out there and
and make some big plays, seal the game,
you know, at the end of it. So, uh, just
happy for him, proud of him, and um, you
know, just uh, love getting to go to
work with him.
>> Remember the time I I went over 60,000?
There's there's only one of 10 in NFL
history.
Yeah, it's uh it brings back a lot of
memories, you know. Um I uh I've been
blessed to play this game for a long
time with a bunch of great players. Um
the cool thing about quarterback and and
my thought about it is uh you know, I
can't throw for any of those yards
without every other 10 player on the
field, you know, 10 other guys that are,
you know, doing their job. Um and so, uh
it's it's really cool. Um, I share it
with so many people and so many
teammates and and a bunch of coaches,
you know, and my family and everybody
that's helped me get there. It's uh you
get in those longevity type uh, you
know,
places where you're you're breaking
those kind of things. It's not, oh, that
was a cool year, a cool two years. I
mean, it's it's been a long time and a
lot of people have sacrificed a lot to
help me out along the way and and I
appreci appreciate each and every single
one of them. Um, but it's uh it's cool.
It's an amazing thing and and sure as
hell glad that we did it. getting a win,
too.
[Music]
>> Going into the game that you were just
going to do what you do and not worry
about it. But were there any moments in
that game or hits or situations where
you felt
>> No.
>> Am I going to be okay?
>> No. Um, no. You can't go out there and
play like that. Um, maybe that's stupid
to think, but that's how I go play. Uh,
you know, I, uh, I just go out there and
play. Um, I think there's, you know,
there was some good stuff I did today. I
think uh you know there's some some
plays I think I can be better and and
try to avoid some more negatives for us.
Um you know and do a better job there.
Um but uh it felt great to get back out
there. I uh you know it's it's um it's
been a long time coming and and uh you
know not only myself but man I was I was
really happy for all um to go through
what he's been through um and work the
way he did um you know through the stuff
that was going on with him. Um just
proud of him and happy for his success
uh to be back out there. I know he loves
being back out there with us and and we
appreciate having him.
>> Can we talk a little bit about the
learning experience you and your team go
through week after week?
>> Yeah, I mean it never stops, right? And
and every single season is different. Um
you have a different team, you got
different opponents. How's it going to
go? You know, do you lose a player to
injury? Do you not? And and it's just
this uh it's this puzzle you got to put
together. Continue to try and get better
and better week in and week out. Find
ways to win football games like we did
today. Um and learn from all the stuff
that could have made this game a lot
easier for us. So, um, it's a whole lot,
you know, more fun to do that at 1 and0
than it is own one and and got to
continue to, you know, correct those
mistakes and bring them to life on game
day when we, uh, when we do the right
stuff.
>> Were you getting antsy the last few
weeks?
>> Uh,
antsy. Uh, no. I mean, I think, uh, I
was just excited to get back out there
and play. Um, happy to, uh, you know,
I've been been on the practice field now
for, I think, three weeks, something
like that. So, felt pretty good about
that. But, uh, no, anytime the season
starts again, I'm excited. Um, and knew,
uh, knew it was going to be a whole lot
of fun to get out there and go to work
with these guys.
>> What did you take away from this win
that
set the tone for the season?
>> Yeah, I mean, it was a great job of
finishing, right? It took uh both sides
of the ball, special teams, everybody to
uh to finish this one out. Um, you know,
we could have done a better job, you
know, late in the game there keeping the
ball um and scoring. um it didn't happen
and our defense rose up to the challenge
and and Lame Man made an unbelievable
play and then you know we had the
opportunity to close the game out too
went backwards for 10 yards which is a
tough way to start it and our guys
battle battled and got us close enough
and then Puka made a great play there at
the end to kind of ice it and u that's
complimentary football right that's hey
we make a mistake defense comes out
makes a play for us hey you know what
we're not going to put you back out on
the field defense we're going to close
this thing out taking a knee and um
those kind of things you can build on
while cleaning up some of the stuff that
you killed some momentum, killed some
drives.
>> Traveling with Devonte Adams today, just
how much does his presence just impact
the offense and him being on the field?
>> Yeah, it's huge. Um, he has a ton of
respect and rightfully so. Um, you know,
he's he's an unbelievable player. Um,
he's made a bunch of big plays. I've
been on the other sideline when I was in
Detroit and and he was doing it to us
when he was in Green Bay. So, uh, you
know, it's uh it's fun to go out there
and work with him, get to, you know,
throw the ball to a guy that's a future
Hall of Famer, unbelievable player. Uh,
I feel I feel lucky.
Thanks.
Can you just walk us through just what
you were going through early in the game
having to leave with the injury come
back and how did you find a way to
settle back in?
>> Yeah. Uh try to come back in here and
make sure I could uh count to 10 on my
on my hands. But uh it was good
come back in here. I was like I felt
like my face was on my face mask and I
was standing up and it was just all the
way down here to the left. But uh just
got some quick some quick stitches and
then got back out there and then uh it
was just yeah trying to find the rhythm
and get back in and get warm back up.
You come back in. They got the AC
blowing on here. I'm laying on the cold
training room table. No bodies in here.
It got cold real fast. But uh it was
exciting to go back out there and uh to
hit somebody all over again. Be like,
man, this is what I prepared for.
>> How about you guys getting you and
Dvonte getting 20 or 19 of the 29
targets in game one? and I know they
want to get it in your hands, but just
talk about that chemistry early on and
how important that's going to be all
season long.
>> Yeah, I think it it speaks to how well
Matthew prepares and uh the our coaches
and the game plan that we put in uh for
this week. Uh it was super exciting when
we're going through the the practice
week. You're all right on Wednesday,
this is what we got on Thursday and
you're feeling really confident walking
into Saturday night walkthroughs and
being like, "All right, we're we're
going out there to execute and we're we
feel pretty confident with the with the
ammo that we have loaded up for the game
plan." So, it was super fun. And then
just for the big boys to to trust us and
to fight that fight that extra second in
the in the down to make sure that we
can't throw the ball down the field.
>> It was your sixyd catch completion from
him that got him past 60,000 care for
your passing yards. Just when you think
about him reaching that accomplishment
like how does that resonate with you?
>> Yeah, it was actually pretty funny. He
came up to me. He was like, "Man, I went
I'm glad the ball went to you and I'm
and I was like, "Oh yeah, like thanks
for like I was like I'm pretty sure the
play was supposed to come to me.
And and then and then as he says that I
like look up on the big screen and it's
like oh Matthew Stafford just passed
60,000 and I'm like a I'm so sorry
brother. I totally missed that. I'm like
just on the field and then I was like a
I understand why you said that. I'm like
I'm grateful because I think it was
funny because the next I didn't say this
to him but I was like my the rookie
record was Carson Wentz. So we got to
break in San Fran. So it's nice that uh
one of those will have Matthew Stafford
and Pukakua tagged to it. Obviously
never want to get injured, but how much
pride do you take in in making some of
those tough plays across the middle of
the field?
>> 100%. I think the little brother and me
like as much as it is to to smile in the
defender's face when you get back up and
you catch that ball and is also to to my
big brothers as well being like, man,
all those times they they paid off. They
the the bounce up game uh came from them
for sure.
>> What did you think about the way that
guys like Steve and Bo also battled on
the line either through injury or Bo
bouncing around from either side?
>> 100%. And I know when I was getting
ready to come in here, Steve had come in
not too late and then you're back in the
huddle and you're we're doing our we're
getting ready to break and we're fist
bumping, dapping up everybody and then
you see him back out there and so um I
think there's a toughness that uh our
group had kind of earned from each other
during our our training camp days of
going against each other and knowing
that we were preparing we were preparing
preparing ourselves for this moment and
uh it's always fun because you know
there are bumps and bruises that come
along the way but to be able to get back
up and uh get ready to hit uh somebody
all over again sorry is uh is something
that we need.
such a big thing here obviously. How do
you describe when the offense was a
little rusty at times seeing what the
defense was doing today?
>> Yeah, I think it's motivation to come
back out there after watching an offense
who you know has great weapons as well.
The struggle on third downs and the
ability for them to get off the field
and so you're like you're confident
going back out on the field like man our
defense is giving them momentum. They're
trying to get it to swing our way. So
it's that extra motivation to go out
there and perform and execute because
you know there there are some plays
where out there they felt like they were
out there for 15 plays. So, you're
trying to make sure that we can get them
off the field and when we go out there,
we can execute to play that the the
two-way game to make sure everybody can
thrive out there.
>> You ever had stitches in a game and come
back in?
>> Um, no. I don't think I've taken too
many shots like that one. I was like, I
I know Henry from before we played in
the the Ponies All-Star game and you
know, it's not a it's never a good sight
when you see a linebacker square to
square to you.
>> Um, honestly, I'm not sure. I just
remember my my I felt like my whole chin
strap and everything was not connected
to my helmet and I knew I was bleeding
somewhere. Tay was talking to me and I
was like, "Uh, there's blood and I don't
know where it's coming from. Please tell
me."
>> When you are playing stitches, you like
is that in your head at all? Are you
able to just play football normally?
>> Uh, try to play football as normally.
There there was some padding and
covering that was covering the eye a
little bit, but then it was like, man,
I'm going out here. Hopefully these
stitches are doing their job because I'm
not hesitating to hit somebody else.
that with the toughness and and
physicality that you bring not only to
the wide receiver room but to the team.
Why was it important for you to to get
back out on the field?
>> Yeah. Well, I I love playing this game
of football. I feel um the excitement
and the want to hit somebody. As much as
Yeah, you take a couple shots here and
there. Uh my excitement to go out there
and hit somebody and be able to play
with the physicality that I enjoy
playing the game of football with is uh
something that that drives me to get
back out there and especially early on
in the game and knowing that it was
something quick and I I was able to go
back out there. I wanted to be out there
as fast as possible for the guys.
>> Were you looking for an opportunity to
get your leg back?
>> Um, on a linebacker, you know, those
ones are tough. You never want to look
out for those guys because then you feel
like you're you're kind of tiptoeing and
then they that's when they get you
again. So, I'm sure it'll it'll come in
another way. But, uh, I wasn't trying to
run back for them.
>> Are you surprised you weren't able to
get more points on the board today? How
much of that is a is a week one thing?
Like you're you're still figuring this
out?
>> Yeah. Um, I think uh definitely a little
bit of the week one thing, but then also
just trying to to figure out what the
defense is doing. They they're making
adjustments to what we're doing out
there at the same time. Um, and for
everybody to communicate and be on the
same page. Uh, we I trust, uh, Matthew
to always go out there and make the
right call, whether it's Canada play,
alert him to, uh, to something else for
a pass concept, but, uh, when we all go
out there, we trust Nine to to get us in
the end zone.
>> Davis Allen battled through the back
last year really hampered him. what it
mean to see him come out, get on the
board early this season and just the way
he's worked through game.
>> Yeah, the general as somebody who come
we came in as rookies together and I've
always been a big fan of his game. So to
see him go out there and be able to
execute and get the first one up there
is is super exciting and then I think it
just speaks to how well that tight end
room has been playing together. I think
from Big Higs um leading the way and
then Kobe and T Ferg in there as well.
So, it's been a a good competition
between those four and they they compete
really well and they communicate I think
is the biggest thing for somebody who
were they were seeing a lot of nickel to
our 12 personnel and stuff like that.
So, trying to figure out and see make
sure we're going to the right guys and
communicating was something that they
all do really well.
>> Can you talk about not playing in the
preseason but now the play at game one
the game shape physicality of the game.
Do you feel like maybe a couple games
down the road and everybody be kind of
like really into the physical part of
the game? Um,
I feel I feel like uh coach does a
really good job of uh making sure we get
enough one-on-one reps during the the
week so we get some good on good and we
get a chance to see what that
physicality kind of looks like and
obviously trying to take care of our
guys. But um I definitely do enjoy uh
being on the preseason sideline and
watching the guys go out there and
seeing the young books try to play and
uh it feels good for my knees so I enjoy
that.
>> Have a good one. And drinks it.